vaxvacationaccess.com 2015-12-05

# VAX | Privacy Policy

** VAX VACATIONACCESS PRIVACY POLICY **

** Effective 12/01/09 **

** Thank you for using VAX VacationAccess **

VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC works with contractors to provide you with access to a variety of benefits described herein as VAX Content which includes but is not limited to VAX applications, products and services.  In order to provide you with these benefits, we may ask you for certain personally identifiable information.  We are committed to safeguarding your privacy and have developed this privacy policy to keep you informed on how we safeguard the information we collect, use and retain.  This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC. does not employ or manage.

** Definitions **

 “VAX” – means the VAX VacationAccess technology owned by VAX that enables the Travel Agency to access the VAX Content and Inventory and make purchases on behalf of their agency and/or customers.

Customer – means an individual for whom the Travel Agency undertakes researching, shopping, booking, or purchasing of products and services on the VAX VacationAccess web sites.

Contractor – means an independent provider of goods or services on behalf of VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC.

Third Party – means a company other than VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC or a domain name other than  [ www.vaxvacationaccess.com ](http://www.vaxvacationaccess.com/) .

**How we Collect  Information**   
We collect travel agency and customer information in a number of ways including, but not limited to,  when you register for VAX, when you sign up to receive emails, when you update your agency profile, when you complete travel agency surveys (e.g. product improvement, pre- or post-training), or requests for agency advisory panel feedback, when you send a comment to the suggestion link on our weekly email or on the website, when you forward an email/webpage to a friend, when you complete online forms (e.g. technical support), when you register your agency to receive commission payments electronically, when you send your client a confirmation or itinerary by email, and when you purchase VAX products and services for your agency or on behalf of your Customer.

The types of information collected include but is not limited to, travel agency name, mailing address, domain address, email address, telephone number, agency description, affiliations, site manager/administrator name, user information, agency bank account/routing number, agency-level and user-level preferencing rules, agency security settings, agency contacts, notes/activities, marketing information, agency payment information, traveler reservation, payment, preferences and profile information.

** How Your Information is Used **

When you register on VAX, we collect agency information (ARC and/or phone number, agency name, address, owner/manager name, GDS and site manager/administrator, agency and user profile, services subscription information.

You have the choice of receiving or not receiving VAX email updates.  If you choose to receive emails, we will send you regular emails featuring the latest deals, exclusive offers, and other information.  You may unsubscribe from the email updates at any time by accessing the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email or by using the link below under our Opt-Out Policy.

The information you supply when you send a request to update your agency profile is a confidential communication between your agency, VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC and Contractors.  We do not collect data from this request, except the total number of requests we receive. 

Information collected through surveys and agency advisory panels may be used by us to improve products, processes and travel agency support.  We may also use some/all of the information to create agency mailing lists and may occasionally send our agencies promotional pieces or other mailings.  Mailing lists compiled from the information you provide will only be used for marketing and promotional efforts.

The information that you supply when you send an online form, suggestion or comment via our email suggestion links are used to reply to your comment.  Your information may also be forwarded to the relevant product team or VAX Technical Support team to further process your comment or help to improve VAX products and services, promotions and support.

The information you supply when you send an email/webpage to a friend or an email itinerary to your customer is used to forward the relevant email or webpage information.  We will not send additional emails or mailings to your Customer.  Your friend must subscribe to our email updates, provide information himself/herself through one of the other available means before we will contact him/her.

The information provided by you to receive commission payments electronically is a confidential communication between you, VAX, and Contractors.  We do not collect data from this request except the total number of requests received.

You may email an itinerary prior to confirming a reservation.  To do so, you will enter your and Customer’s email addresses to send the itinerary email.  Upon confirmation of Customer’s reservation, you can send an e-travel confirmation to Customer.  The VAX email address will always default to your agency address, however, if you elect to enter Customer’s email address, all subsequent changes e.g. airline flight schedule change will be sent directly to the customer’s email address.     

The information you provide to make purchases online is used to confirm Customer’s reservation or your subscription to VAX products and services.  We will not share this information with any outside parties except to the extent necessary to process your request e.g. credit card authorizations, or to populate your online database including customer contacts, profiles, trip plans and agency accounting tools. 

We may also use non-identifying or aggregate information to improve our website, track promotional success, and/or to share website usage information with our contractors, third parties or other business affiliates.  This information may include, but is not limited to: number of page views, visitor sessions, clicks, and unique visitors; session length; browser type; top site paths; and, top referring domains.  Not all of this information is shared with our business affiliates, but some aggregate numbers such as page views on a particular page during a particular time frame may be shared.  However, no personally identifiable information about you will be shared with any contractor or third party.

**Third Parties**   
We have relationships with other carefully selected companies that we allow to place ads on our web pages to bring you offers that may be of interest to you.  As a result of your visit to our site, ad server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address, and click stream information.  The use of such information is governed by the privacy policy of these other companies. 

We may assist travel agencies by automatically registering you with third party providers of products and services; however, t **hird party providers with whom we share or you share your personally identifiable information may have their own privacy policies.   These tools by their nature may gather personally identifiable information and credit card information from you to complete your purchase request.  Personally identifiable information collected by these providers is subject to their privacy policies and you are encouraged to review said policies before providing any personally identifiable information.  VAX VacationAccess Worldwide, LLC shall have no obligation or liability of any kind to you respecting the privacy policies of any third party providers, the failure of any of them to adopt a privacy policy or follow their respective privacy policies, or their use of your personally identifiable information.**

Except as noted above, we do not disclose any information on you or your customer without having obtained your consent, as applicable, or unless bound by any statue or regulation to do so.

 **Opt-In Information**

** If you wish to receive information about VAX news, products and services via email, you may access the sign up forms throughout the website.  **

**Opt-Out Policy**   
To unsubscribe from VAX emails, you can visit the unsubscribe page at  <http://www.vaxvacationaccess.com/unsubscribe.aspx>.

If you want to prevent a third party ad server from sending and reading cookies on your computer, you must visit the ad server’s site and opt out.  Currently, we have relationships with the following third-party ad server (click to visit their Web sites and review their privacy statements): 24/7 Real Media, Inc. at  [ http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html ](http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html) .

If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses.  If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check our website periodically.

 **About Cookies**  
Cookies are pieces of information that get stored on your computer when you visit or use various websites. Cookies are not harmful to your computer; they simply "remember" information. VAX uses cookies to remember your account number, name, and user preferences and to work efficiently. It helps the efficiency of your computer if you "clean" or remove your computer's cookies periodically. 

As a general guideline, remove cookies from your computer:

  * On a quarterly basis.
  * When you see enhancements or new functionality in VAX.
  * When VAX appears to be running slowly. 

**Important!**

To ensure that VAX applications function properly on your computer, the Internet Options Privacy setting must allow first-party cookies from  [ www.vaxvacationaccess.com ](http://www.vaxvacationaccess.com/) . 

**Security**   
We understand the security and trust obligations of ourselves and travel agents and strive to implement the highest standards and achieve the highest levels of security in the travel industry. We have audited security processes and perform strong internal tests and multiple external intrusion tests to ensure our systems and products are protecting the data and security of travel agents. Our certifications include the **AmbironTrustWave Trusted CommerceSM Seal**.
